I really feel that there is this
collective subconscious rage that is
just boiling in women and it's coming up
in so many ways we see we see in the
media and what's going on is this
unknown rage that comes up in in many
different ways and on one hand it needs
to come out we need to clear it it needs
to be expressed it needs to be
acknowledged on the other hand it's not
enough this is only like this is
breaking the ice so that the next step
of evolution can you know consciousness
can start coming through and that's what
I'm lacking in women it's really to take
responsibility for what we do as women
in our manipulation in our seduction in
our control and and it's so easy for
women to say but that's just because
we're angry and mended this and
patriarchy but it's it's such a lack of
responsibility and this women really
need to know because we could say we
could look at say me too
which has been kind of ongoing for a
long time and as still a massive force
and we can say that it's it's brought up
a lot of male shadows it's brought
showing up a lot of male behavior that
is just inexcusable should not happen
and it's it's certainly you could say
started as a positive thing but then you
also have like there's there's perhaps a
danger of its slipping into a very
simplistic narrative of men as only
aggressors women as only victims is that
something that you're worried about I'm
very worried about that because what it
feels like is it has displayed the male
shadow but who talks about the female
shadow the rage that that women are
expressing blindly and projecting onto
which ever situation and which ever men
that they can this is not an empowered
woman this is not the empowered feminine
this is the underbelly of feminism this
is when feminism goes wrong this is not
the few
it's not the future to blame and to
project and to persecute you explain
what you mean a bit more about when
feminism goes wrong when feminism goes
wrong we allow the collective rage to
act out through us so we see every
situation we see every man we see every
encounter with the lens of of the victim
and we're so angry about it and it's
it's boiling in every woman it's right
under the surface so she will quickly
snap if if this if there's a reason or
if there's an apparent reason because
it's so strong it hasn't discharged it's
in the collective and that rage needs to
discharge but it needs to discharge in
an intelligent way not in an unconscious
way and you said before that that rage
is often directed at men not showing up
I'd say it's it's two-way because yes
it's it's targeted at men not showing up
or they are causing it but it's very
often projected out to men that are
actually trying to show up that is
actually engaging in with will engaging
with women and actually talking about
these things so that's that's because
then we bring up this topic and then
it's so easy for women to tap into that
collective pool of rage and it just
comes out this is this is where women
need to step up and take responsibility
and stop blaming men it's pointless
we need to transcend this we can't solve
this we can't solve this problem from
the steps from the same level we need to
transcend and look at how am i adding to
this dynamic as a woman because we are
we are co-creating it in perfect harmony
if women are angry we absolutely need to
take responsibility for getting
ourselves to another place if you want a
more direct experience of some of the
topics in this film rebel wisdom is
running workshops for men to grow up and
show up more in the war
check the website for more great films
such as the first full-length
documentary on jordan peterson and for
details of our upcoming events
[Music]
you